# Leonardo Boulitreau

#### Al Audio Researcher

★ leonardoboulitreau.github.io | Meonardoboulitreau@gmail.com | Impleonardoboulitreau

### About

I am a researcher in the intersection of artificial intelligence and audio, with over 4 years of experience and a solid background in signal processing. Currently, I work as an AI Speech Researcher @CPqD. My research efforts are directed towards developing human-machine interaction systems that are more affective and human-empowering.

### Skills

**Deep Learning** PyTorch, Tensorflow, HuggingFace, ONNX, Gradio, MLFlow **Speech Frameworks** Coqui, SpeechBrain, Amphion, ESPNET, NeMo, Kaldi

**Tools** Docker, Git, Kubernetes

Cloud AWS, GCP

**Programming** Python, C, C++, MATLAB, LaTeX **Languages** Portuguese, English, French

**Competences** Paper Implementation, Experiment Design, Team Collaboration

## **Experience**

Al+Speech Researcher São Paulo, Brazi

2023 - Present

- Currently evaluating synthetic LLM textual data for ASR domain-specific improvement.
- Evaluated and improved fairness on multi-accented speech recognition for the Brazilian Portuguese language.
- Improved the company's emotion recognition system in production, in terms of speed and performance, by developing a 2-step emotion recognition architecture (ECAPA-TDNN + HuBERT Emotion Classifier)
- Enriched the company's call center customer profiling product by developing and sending to production speech age and gender classifier
  models.

Fellow Master São Paulo, Brazi

@CPQD - RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CENTER IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS

2021 - 2023

- · Developed neural customer-oriented expressive text-to-speech models for the Brazilian Portuguese language.
- Enabled customers to edit the synthesized audios' prosody in a fine-grained way by implementing character-level prosody control on the ONNX version of the FastPitch TTS model.
- Conducted several subjective perceptual experiments to evaluate synthetic audio quality, naturalness and expresiveness.

Laboratory Intern Paraíba, Brazi

@ LPS - PROTOTYPING AND SIMULATION LABORATORY

2020 - 2021

- Enhanced lab automation by designing neural speech commands recognition systems.
- Encapsulated the ASR system in a local private LoRa network for IoT purposes.
- Enabled long distance voice control by developing a wearable prototype with an embedded microphone.

### **Education**

### M.Sc. in Computer Engineering

São Paulo, Brazil

@UNICAMP (STATE UNIVERSITY OF CAMPINAS)

2021 - 2024

- GPA: 5/5
- Thesis: Cross-Speaker Style Transfer for TTS based on Singing Voice Conversion Data Augmentation, Style Filtering, and F0 Matching 💽
- Study On The Cross Modality of Pre-Training: Can models pre-trained in different domains adapt to a different one on a downstream task? 🖸
- Study Meta-learning strategies to build a few-shot emotion classifier.

### **Exchange Student (Excellence Scholarship)**

Paris, France

2019 - 2020

· Studying Machine Learning, Statistics, Optimization, Digital Signal Processing, IoT and Telecommunications.

### **B.Sc. in Electronic Engineering**

Paraíba, Brazil

2015 - 2021

@UFPB (STATE UNIVERSITY OF PARAÍBA)

• GPA: 8.38/10

@TÉLÉCOM PARIS 👚

- Research Wind velocity estimation via the Extended Kalman Filter (DSP).
- Participated in the Electronics team of the national Aerodesign competition.
- Differential and Integral Calculus Tutor.